{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Austroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Uralic","Sino-Tibetan","Kra–Dai"],"question":"The language 'Vietnamese' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ear","incorrectAnswers":["Nose","Mouth","Eyes"],"question":"With what body part is otology involved?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Richard III'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Zürich","incorrectAnswers":["Paris","Prague","Barcelona"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Switzerland?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Christian Bale","incorrectAnswers":["John Hawkes","Jeremy Renner","Mark Ruffalo"],"question":"Who won the 2010 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Dicky Eklund in The Fighter?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Frankfort","incorrectAnswers":["Louisville","Lexington","Bowling Green"],"question":"What is the capital of Kentucky?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Crete","incorrectAnswers":["Santorini","Corfu","Rhodes"],"question":"What is the largest island of Greece, home to the ancient ruined Minoan palace of Knossos?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Indonesia","incorrectAnswers":["Turkey","Saudi Arabia","Thailand"],"question":"In which country would you find the island of Bali?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Enigma","incorrectAnswers":["Mystery","Paradox","Riddle"],"question":"What Was The Name Given To The Coding Machine Used By The Germans In World War II?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tim Burton","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Batman Returns?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A murder","incorrectAnswers":["A fall","A cast","A barren"],"question":"What is the word for a group of crows?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Joey","incorrectAnswers":["A Maggot","A Piglet","A Poult"],"question":"A young kangaroo is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Inventor of the printing press.","incorrectAnswers":["Scientist who discovered The Theory of Relativity.","Industrialist who revolutionised mass-production techniques. ","Started the Protestant Reformation."],"question":"Which of the following describes Johann Gutenberg?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British band released the studio album 'A Rush of Blood to the Head'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"An unkindness","incorrectAnswers":["A charm","A run","A cete"],"question":"What is the word for a group of ravens?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The Panama Canal","incorrectAnswers":["The Golden Gate Bridge","The Bay Bridge","The Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta"],"question":"What engineering achievement made it much easier to sail between the Atlantic and Pacific oceans?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Volleyball","Cycling","Badminton"],"question":"With which sport is Billie Jean King associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Washington, D.C.","incorrectAnswers":["New York","Los Angeles","Chicago"],"question":"What is the capital city of The United States of America?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George III","incorrectAnswers":["George IV","William IV","Victoria"],"question":"Which British monarch reigned during the American Revolutionary War?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Bluebird","incorrectAnswers":["Dragonfly","Sparrow","Finch"],"question":"What was the name of the vehicle in which Sir Malcom Campbell broke the 300mph barrier in 1935?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Giovanni Boccaccio","incorrectAnswers":["Dante Alighieri","Agatha Christie","Stephenie Meyer"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Le Décaméron'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alphonse Daudet","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","Oscar Wilde","Leo Tolstoy"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Letters From My Windmill'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Boston Bruins","incorrectAnswers":["Boston United","Boston Whitecaps","Boston Bucks"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Boston?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Macedonia","incorrectAnswers":["France","Greece","Estonia"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Skopje?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1984","incorrectAnswers":["1979","1989","1994"],"question":"The Terminator was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"CFCs","incorrectAnswers":["HFCs","NFCs","OFCs"],"question":"Which chemical compounds, responsible for breaking down the ozone layer, were the subject of a 1987 treaty?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Sporting Kansas City","incorrectAnswers":["Kansas City Yankees","Kansas City Steelers","Real Kansas City"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Kansas City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Basseterre","incorrectAnswers":["Manama","Podgorica","Port-au-Prince"],"question":"What is the capital city of Saint Kitts and Nevis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Aristotle","incorrectAnswers":["Ludwig Wittgenstein","Immanuel Kant","John Locke"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, then, is not an act, but a habit'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Two detectives hunt a serial killer who uses the deadly sins as his motives.","incorrectAnswers":["Prisoners of war plan to escape from a German camp during World War II.","A human soldier is sent from 2029 to 1984 to stop an almost indestructible cyborg killing machine.","The story an English officer who successfully united and led the Arab tribes during World War I."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Seven?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephenie Meyer","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Vance","Brandon Sanderson","Robert A. Heinlein"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Twilight'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"South America","incorrectAnswers":["The Middle East","Central Asia","Europe"],"question":"From which part of the world do lima beans originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Christopher Columbus","incorrectAnswers":["Napoleon Bonaparte","Martin Luther","Marco Polo"],"question":"Which of these people was an Italian explorer who landed in America?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golden Bear","incorrectAnswers":["Black Tiger","Silver Swan","Red Eagle"],"question":"What was Jack Nicklaus' nickname?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Chris Columbus","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Home Alone?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mandrill","incorrectAnswers":["Lemur","Macaque","Tamarin"],"question":"Which monkey has patches of red on its rear end? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Kinks","incorrectAnswers":["Bobby Fuller Four","Carl Perkins","Talking Heads"],"question":"The song 'You Really Got Me' had a well-known cover by Van Halen, but who recorded the original?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Purple","Red"],"question":"What Colour Is Sonic the Hedgehog?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"My mama always said life was like a box of chocolates. You never know what you're gonna get.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Very nice!\"","\"Say hello to my little friend!\"","\"Nobody makes me bleed my own blood. Nobody!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Forrest Gump'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sheltered harbor","incorrectAnswers":["Bright Sun","Golden Shores","Trading Post"],"question":"What is the meaning of \"Honolulu\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Powerful Indian King who established a large empire by conquest before converting to Buddhism.","incorrectAnswers":["Queen of England from 1558 to her death in 1603. Cemented England as a Protestant country, defeated Spanish Armada.","Explorer, first European to reach India and establish a route for imperialism.","Spiritual Teacher and founder of Buddhism."],"question":"Which of the following describes Asoka?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Catholicism","incorrectAnswers":["Hinduism","Judaism","Islam"],"question":"What religion is associated with the word 'Papal'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kate Bush","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","John Lennon","George Michael"],"question":"Which British recording artist, singer, songwriter, musician and record producer released the studio album 'Never for Ever'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Berlin","incorrectAnswers":["Boston","Chicago","Foreigner"],"question":"Which band sang the love song 'Take My Breath Away' for the movie 'Top Gun'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Samuel Pepys","incorrectAnswers":["Anne Frank","Lewis Chertsey","Henry Rollings"],"question":"Who Wrote A Famous Diary Between 1660 & 1669?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iraq","incorrectAnswers":["Saudi Arabia","United Arab Emirates","Kuwait"],"question":"In which middle eastern country is the city of Kirkuk?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Romania","incorrectAnswers":["Albania","Kyrgyzstan","Japan"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Three vertical bands of blue, yellow, and red.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Puffin","incorrectAnswers":["Albatross","Penguin","Dodo"],"question":"What bird is associated with Lundy Island?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"A Gladiator","incorrectAnswers":["A Centurion","A Dominus","A Caesar"],"question":"What was the name of someone who fought professionally in Roman arenas?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Earl Of Sandwich ","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel D Wich","King Sandwich","Judge Sandwich"],"question":"After Who Was The Sandwich Named?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Johnny Depp","incorrectAnswers":["John Cusack","Harrison Ford","Sean Penn"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Captain Jack Sparrow in Pirates of the Caribbean?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Recoil","incorrectAnswers":["Muzzle flash","Backfire","Forward thrust"],"question":"What is the term for the backward momentum that a person feels after firing a gun?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mojave","incorrectAnswers":["Sonoran","Arizonan","Baja"],"question":"Name the desert located in South East California.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jason","incorrectAnswers":["Freddie","Mike","Chuckie"],"question":"What Is The Name Of The Bad Guy In The Friday The 13th Series?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Crash","incorrectAnswers":["Brokeback Mountain","Capote","Good Night, and Good Luck."],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2005?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Forty","incorrectAnswers":["Thirty","Twenty","Fifty"],"question":"How fast (mph) can a kangaroo hop?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Olympus","incorrectAnswers":["Sinai","Everest","Marathon"],"question":"Which Greek mountain was known as the home of the gods?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Venezuela","incorrectAnswers":["Trinidad and Tobago","Chile","Grenada"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Brazil?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Tuvalu is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Colombia","incorrectAnswers":["Dominican Republic","Brazil","Ecuador"],"question":"In which country is the city of Bogotá?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Hopman Cup","incorrectAnswers":["The Indianapolis 500","The Open Championship","The Kentucky Derby"],"question":"Which of these is a Tennis competition?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dogs","incorrectAnswers":["Plants","Swans","Church architecture"],"question":"What is Cynology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Guns N' Roses","incorrectAnswers":["AC/DC","Metallica","Whitesnake"],"question":"Which band has Slash as its lead guitarist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Great Barrier Reef","incorrectAnswers":["The Northern Lights","The Galapagos Islands","The Mariana Trench"],"question":"What is the name of the natural wonder that stretches over 1,250 miles off the east coast of Australia?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bassoon","incorrectAnswers":["Banjo","Harpsichord","Bongo"],"question":"Which of these is a woodwind instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bobby McFerrin","incorrectAnswers":["David Naughton","Gary Numan","Falco"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1988 with Don't Worry Be Happy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mercury","incorrectAnswers":["Silver","Iron","Titanium"],"question":"Which Metal is Also Known As Quicksilver?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Eugène Delacroix","incorrectAnswers":["‎Salvador Dalí","Paul Cézanne","Jackson Pollock"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Liberty leading the people\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Florence","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Venice","Milan"],"question":"What is the name of the Italian city-state in which the Renaissance began?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1964","incorrectAnswers":["1944","1980","1992"],"question":"In which US election year were the supporters of the Democratic candidate paraphrasing the popular song \"Hello Dolly\" to \"Hello Lyndon\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Cable Guy","incorrectAnswers":["Liar Liar","Ace Ventura: Pet Detective","The Truman Show"],"question":"Which Jim Carrey film features the quote, 'Hi. Is there a problem with your service?'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Treehouse of Horror","incorrectAnswers":["Spooky Springfield","The Halloween Haunt","Evergreen Menace"],"question":"What are The Simpsons Halloween specials known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American singer and songwriter released the single 'Like a Prayer'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ostrich","incorrectAnswers":["Peacock","Emu","Emperor Penguin"],"question":"Name the largest living bird.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A branch of logic focusing on part-whole relationships","incorrectAnswers":["The study of weather patterns","A new-age religion that focuses on astrology","The process by which toxins are removed from the body"],"question":"What is Mereology?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Bhutan","Nepal","Thailand"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Bangladesh?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tajikistan","incorrectAnswers":["Burundi","Sao Tome and Principe","Seychelles"],"question":"Dushanbe is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bowdlerize","incorrectAnswers":["Censor","Redact","Amend"],"question":"What term means to prudishly edit vulgar bits out of a written work, named after someone who did it to Shakespeare?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Xhosa","incorrectAnswers":["Tamil","Chewa","Berber"],"question":"Which of these languages would you find spoken in South Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Colorado","incorrectAnswers":["Blanco","Negro","Verde"],"question":"What is the Spanish word for 'reddish-brown' that signifies a cigar class?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Johannes V. Jensen","incorrectAnswers":["Hans Christian Andersen","Søren Kierkegaard","Agatha Christie"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Fall of the King'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"A glacier","incorrectAnswers":["A river","An earthquake","A tornado"],"question":"What phenomenon is responsible for Minnesota's 10,000 lakes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Realism","incorrectAnswers":["Suprematism","Fauvism","Modernism"],"question":"The painting \"Olympia\" by Édouard Manet is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Honduras","incorrectAnswers":["Dominican Republic","Mexico","Cuba"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Tegucigalpa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Carrie","incorrectAnswers":["Annie","Megan","Emily"],"question":"In an early Stephen King novel, which titular character is a student at Ewen High?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'Under Pressure'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Connery","George Lazenby","Daniel Craig"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Live and Let Die?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Warren Harding","incorrectAnswers":["Theodore Roosevelt","Andrew Jackson ","Gerald Ford"],"question":"Who was the 29th president of the USA, in term during the period 1921–1923?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Real & Imaginary","incorrectAnswers":["True & False","Big & Small","Logical & Intuitive"],"question":"What are the 2 parts of complex numbers known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"United States","incorrectAnswers":["Cote d'Ivoire","Sweden","Uruguay"],"question":"Which of these countries has red on its flag?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Japan","India"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.de' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"100 Metres","incorrectAnswers":["Javelin","Pole Vault","800 Metres"],"question":"In A Decathlon What Is The First Event","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Marie Antoinette","incorrectAnswers":["Eleanor of Aquitaine","Margaret of Provence","Maria Theresa"],"question":"Which Queen of France was beheaded in 1793?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1975","incorrectAnswers":["1970","1980","1985"],"question":"One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles and Mary Lamb","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Tales from Shakspeare'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1999","incorrectAnswers":["1993","1996","2002"],"question":"In which year was American Beauty released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Warren Commission","incorrectAnswers":["The Truman Commission","The Roosevelt Commission","The Eisenhower Commission"],"question":"What was the name of the commission that was appointed to investigate the assassination of US President John F. Kennedy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"G. W. F. Hegel","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Jean-Paul Sartre","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Only one man ever understood me, and he didn’t understand me'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"CR-V","incorrectAnswers":["Impala","Polo","Phantom"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Honda?","difficulty":"medium"},